Monica?
摩妮卡？
What time is it?
現在幾點？
Nine.
9點
But it's dark out.
可是外面還很黑
That's because you always sleep till noon,silly.
那是因為你老睡到中午，傻瓜
This is what nine looks like.
9點就是這麼黑
I guess I'll get washed up then.
那我該梳洗一下
Watch that sunrise.
準備看日出
I'm getting tired of always sneaking around.
我不想再偷偷摸摸了
Me too. What if we went away for the weekend? No interruptions.
我知道，我也是 不然我們去外面渡週末 就沒人打擾我們
We could be naked the entire time.
還可以赤身裸體
All weekend? That's a whole lot of naked.
整個週末？那可是很長
I'll say I have a conference and you can have a chef thing.
我可以說我去開會 你就說去參加廚師研討
I wanted to go to this culinary fair in Jersey!
我一直想參加澤西的烹飪大會
Okay. You know you're not,though.
不過你去的不是那裡
-Let's go. -Okay. Wait.
走吧
What about Joey?
等等，喬伊怎麼辦？
The One with the Kips
本集播出：「誰進誰出」
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
I'm going to a culinary fair in Jersey this weekend.
你們知道我這週末要幹嘛嗎？去紐澤西參加烹飪大會
How weird! Chandler just said he's got a conference there.
錢德剛才說要去那裡開會
That's funny. Seems like Chandler's conference could've been...
真有意思 錢德應該可以
...in Connecticut or Vermont.
去康州或維蒙開會
I'm not in charge of where the conference is held.
我又不能決定在哪裡開會
Do you want people to think it's fake? It's a real conference.
難道你希望大家認為我造假？ 因為我可沒說謊
-ls Rachel here? -No,she's out shopping.
瑞秋在嗎？我要找她
她出去逛街了
-Damn! -What's going on?
可惡 怎麼了？
I told Emily to come.
我叫艾蜜莉來
And I just need to,you know, talk to Rachel about it.
所以我得趕快跟瑞秋說
Wait a minute.
等等
When Emily comes, you won't see Rachel anymore?
艾蜜莉來了之後 你真的就不見瑞秋了？
I'm focusing on the "I get to see my wife" part...
我現在只能專心想著 「我可以見我老婆」
...and not on the part that makes me do this.
不去想我快胃潰瘍的事
So you'll never be in a room together?
你們再也不能共處一室？
How will that even work?
這怎麼可能？
I have no idea. I mean....
我也不知道
But I assure you, I will figure it out.
但是我一定會想到辦法
It doesn't seem like it'll work.
看起來實在不可能…
Hi,guys.
大家好 嗨
嘿
What's going on?
怎麼了？
We're flipping Monica's mattress.
我們正要幫摩妮卡翻床墊
So I'm thinking,basically, we pick it up and then we flip it.
我認為應該先抬起來再翻過來
That's better than my way.
這方法比我的主意好
Hey guys,would you flip mine too?
你們順便幫我翻
Oh,man.
受不了
Oh,look! A letter from my mom.
我媽寄信來
So,Rach?
瑞秋，
You know how Emily's coming?
你知道艾蜜莉要來
Oh,yeah. I know.
我知道啊
Can you hear anything?
聽得到嗎？
Yeah,somebody just said, "Can you hear anything?"
當然，剛剛有人說 「聽得到嗎？」
Hey,Joey's ass.
喬伊的大屁股
What are you doing?
你在做什麼？
Remember when they fought and broke up...
記得上次他們吵架分手時
...and we were stuck here all night with no food?
我們卡在房裡沒東西可吃嗎？
When Ross said "Rachel" at the wedding, I figured it'd happen again.
羅斯在婚禮上說出瑞秋名字後 我猜舊戲可能會重演
So I hid this in here.
所以我在這裡藏了這些東西
Candy bars,crossword puzzles....
有糖果，猜謎…
Mad Libs! Mine!
還有瘋狂字謎，我要
-Okay,"Name of someone in room."
-Chandler.
好，「說出房裡某人的名字」
錢德
Come on,seriously.
拜託，正經一點
What do you got in here? Magazines,Doritos
還有什麼？雜誌、洋芋片
Condoms?
保險套？
You don't know how long we'll be in here.
誰曉得會在這裡待多久
We may have to repopulate the Earth.
搞不好我們還得負責 繁衍人類後代
And condoms are the way to do that?
戴保險套還想繁衍後代？
Anyway,it all boils down to this.
有個關鍵問題
-The last time I talked to Emily -Oh,my God! Our dog died!
上次我跟艾蜜莉通電話 天啊，我的狗死了
-What? -Oh,my God! LaPooh,our dog!
什麼？ 天啊，拉普死了
LaPooh's still alive?
拉普還活著？
Sorry.
對不起
It says he was hit by an ice cream truck and dragged for...
我媽說它被冰淇淋車撞到
...nineteen blocks!
還被拖了...19條街
-Oh,my God. -Sweetie,we heard you crying.
我的天啊 我們聽到你在哭
-Please don't cry. -It's LaPooh!
別哭了
I know,it's LaPooh right now but it'll get better.
是拉普 過幾天就沒事了
I can't believe it! We're here!
不可思議，我們到了
Chocolates on the pillows! I love that!
枕頭上還放巧克力 我最愛這套
You should live with Joey. Rolos everywhere.
那你應該跟喬伊住 到處都有巧克力糖
This is so great. No one's gonna bother us.
太好了，沒人會來打擾我們
And we're gonna do it.
我們可以盡情纏綿
I'm gonna do it with Monica!
我要跟摩妮卡上床了
Chandler,stop yelling that you and I are gonna do it!
錢德，上床就上床，別窮嚷嚷
-I'll be right back. -Okay.
我馬上回來
Oh,yes!
萬歲
Get in here. There's a high-speed car chase on!
摩妮卡快來 電視正在轉播警匪公路追逐戰
We're switching rooms.
我們要換房間
Oh,dear God! They gave us glasses!
天啊，他們給了我們玻璃杯！
The glasses have lipstick on them.
杯子上有口紅印
Who knows what else they didn't change?
如果連杯子都沒換 誰曉得還有哪些東西沒換
You wanna switch rooms because they didn't switch the glasses?
飯店沒換杯子你就要換房間？
I didn't wanna say anything, but the carpet smells too.
我本來不想說 地毯也有點臭
I want this weekend to be perfect. We can change rooms,can't we?
親愛的，我只是希望 過個完美的週末 換個房間嘛
Okay,but let's do it now. Chopper Five just lost its feed!
好吧，要換快換 5號直升機剛跟丟了
Forget it.
算了
You know how there was something I wanted to talk to you about?
記得我上次有事告訴你嗎？
Oh,yeah.
對
I'm trying to work things out with Emily.
你知道我很希望跟艾蜜莉合好
Well,there's this...
不過…
...one thing.
有件事...
Here goes.
我要說了
I made a promise that
我答應她…
-What? -Your nose is bleeding.
什麼？ 你流鼻血
-Oh,God! -You're bleeding.
天啊
Oh,not again. This happened when my grandfather died.
別又來了 我祖父過世時也一樣
Sorry.
實在是…抱歉
Gross.
Okay. So I'm sorry. What did you want to tell me?
好了，對不起 你剛要說什麼？
Sorry. Sorry.
抱歉
I can't see you anymore.
我不能再見你了
I know,it's ridiculous. I can't see you,either. All right.
我知道，真離譜 我也看不到你 好吧
I'm just gonna go shove a bunch of tissues in my nose.
我得塞一坨衛生紙到鼻子裡
Hey,do you wanna tell me while I do that?
我邊塞你邊說好了
I'm good.
算了
-I think you'll like this room more. -Okay,great.
你們可能會喜歡這間房 太好了
They say he's only got half a tank left.
聽說他只剩下一半的汽油
Half a tank? Still lots of high-speed chasing to do!
一半？那還可以跑很久哩
-I'll bet he's heading for Canada. -They always do.
他一定是想去加拿大 每次都用同一招
-We're switching rooms again. -What? Why?
我們必須換房間 什麼？為什麼？
This has a garden view. We paid for an ocean view.
這間房是花園景觀 我們訂的是觀海房
Our last ocean-view room was unacceptable to you.
只剩一間觀海房 可是你們不喜歡
-The carpet smelled. -Like ocean?
那間房的地毯有味道 大海的味道？
No,like feet.
是腳臭味
Excuse me. Can I talk to you over here for just a second?
失陪，我可以跟你談一下嗎？
錢德 來了
These clowns want to take us for a ride. I won't let them.
這些小人想佔我們便宜 我才沒那麼蠢
We're not a couple of suckers.
我們可不是呆頭鵝
I hear you,Mugsy.
說得好，大姐頭
All these rooms are fine.
這些房間都還好啊
Just pick one so I can watch the
請你趕快選定，讓我看…
Have a perfect,magical weekend together with you?
讓我跟你一起好好渡假
Oh,man,he almost hit a gas truck.
天啊，他差點撞上油罐車
Do you ever watch Baywatch?
你看不看「海灘遊俠」？
-This one I like. -Nothing. Nothing. It's over. Damn it!
我喜歡這間 沒了，結束了
This is regularly scheduled programming!
竟然沒有延長時間
-I wanted to see them talk to his neighbors. -Well,I'm standing right here...
我想看他們訪問鄰居 我就在這
-...you could talk to me. -You didn't know him.
你可以跟我聊天 你又不認識歹徒
Can we turn the TV off?
可以關掉電視嗎？
Do we really want to spend the weekend like this?
難道整個週末都要看電視？
Am I getting in the way of the room-switching fun?
抱歉，我是不是 妨礙你換房間了？
Don't blame me for tonight.
你火大可別怪到我身上
Who should I blame? The nice bellman?
否則該怪誰？那個倒霉的服務生？
Or the idiot who thought he could drive...
或許該怪那個以為用半箱汽油
...from Albany to Canada on half a tank of gas?
可以從紐約跑到加拿大的傢伙
Do not speak ill of the dead.
不要說死者的壞話
We're supposed to be spending a romantic weekend together.
我們出來是為了過浪漫週末
What's the matter?
你到底哪裡有毛病？
I just want to watch a little television.
我只是想看點電視 有何不對？
Jeez,relax,Mom.
放輕鬆嘛，老媽
What did you say?
你說什麼？
I said,"Jeez,relax,Mon."
我說，「放輕鬆，小摩」
You know what,Chandler? You like fast getaways? Watch this.
你喜歡看高速逃忘？ 現在就看好了
I don't like fast getaways, I like car chases.
我不喜歡看高速逃忘 我要看的是飛車逃忘
-Hey,what's up? -Hey.
嗨
I've been wanting to tell you something and I just have to get it out.
瑞秋，我一直有話要告訴你
我非說不可
Okay. What's up?
什麼事？
Okay,before I tell you I just have to know...
在我說話之前，你確定
...is your nose okay?
不會再流鼻血？
Are all the other family pets in good health?
你家其他的寵物都很健康？
Well,Davey's still pining after LaPooh...
大衛還在傷心拉普過世
...but,you know,he's a tough little turtle.
不過它是支堅強的小烏龜
You know how you said to do whatever it takes to fix my marriage?
你上次說我應該 不惜代價挽救婚姻？
Yeah,I told you to give Emily whatever she wants.
對，我叫你 答應艾蜜莉所有要求
And while that was good advice, you should know that what she wants...
你建議不錯 不過我必須告訴你她開的條件
...is for me not to see you anymore.
就是叫我永遠不能再見你
That's crazy! You can't do that. What are you going to tell her?
太扯了，你才做不到 你要怎麼告訴她？
Oh,my God!
天啊
You've already agreed to this.
你已經答應了 對不對？
It's awful,I know.
我知道自己很惡劣
But I have to do this if I want my marriage to work.
我心情也很糟糕 但是這是挽救婚姻的唯一方法
And I do. I have to make this marriage work. I have to.
我很希望跟她合好 必須挽救這段婚姻
But the good thing is,we can still see each other until she gets here.
好在我們在她抵達之前 還可以繼續見面
Lucky me! Oh,my God! That is good news,Ross!
我真幸運 天啊，這真是好消息
That's the best news I've heard since LaPooh died!
自從拉普過世之後 最大的好消息
You have no idea what a nightmare this has been. This is so hard.
你不知道我有多難過 我也很痛苦
Oh,yeah,really? Is it,Ross?
是嗎？真的嗎，羅斯？
-Let me make this easier for you. -What are you doing?
我可以為你減輕壓力 你做什麼？
-Storming out. -It's your apartment.
憤而出走  瑞秋，這是你家
Yeah? Well,that's how mad I am!
你看我有多火大
Damn Rolos!
臭巧克力糖
You're back! How was your conference?
你回來了 嘿 這次出差如何？
It was terrible. I fought with my colleagues the entire time.
糟透了 我跟…同事吵架 到回來前都沒合好
Are you kidding with this?
你開玩笑？
So your weekend was a bust?
也就是整個週末都泡湯？
No,I got to see Donald Trump waiting for an elevator.
也不會，我看到 唐納川普等電梯
You know,at the Taj Mahal he has his own private glass elevator.
他在泰姬陵有私人玻璃電梯
That's right. Made by Otis Elevators.
都由歐狄斯電梯公司生產
And they don't usually do glass.
那家公司很少做玻璃電梯
What kinds of stuff do you know?
你腦袋裡都裝什麼啊？
You're back too.
嗨 你也回來了
Could I talk to you for a second?
對，錢德，可以出來一下嗎？
-How was your chef thing? -lt was awful.
烹飪大會好玩嗎？ 糟透了
Some people don't appreciate good food.
有些人根本不會欣賞美食
Maybe the food tasted good at first...
你的食物可能看起來很美味
...but then made everybody vomit and have diarrhea.
吃下去卻害人上吐下瀉
錢德 摩妮卡
How much was the room? I'll pay my half.
旅館費用多少？ 我要付我那一半
Fine. $300.
很好，300元
$300?
300元？
Just think of it as $25 per room.
就想成每間25元
What are you guys woofing about?
你們鬼叫什麼？
Chandler stole a 20 from my purse!
錢德從我皮包偷了20元紙鈔
不會吧？
I was only stealing it back, the one that she stole from me.
因為摩妮卡先偷我的錢 我只是拿回來
Stealing and now lying.
這人不但是小偷還說謊
You know what? Now that I think about it...
現在回頭想想，
...I constantly find myself without 20s,and you...
我老沒20元
...always have lots.
你皮夾裡倒是很多
You should've seen the look on her face.
你們應該看看她當時的表情
I don't want Rachel to hate me. I don't know what to do.
我不希望瑞秋恨我 真不知道該怎麼辦
-You want my advice? -Yes. Please.
你要聽我的建議嗎？請說
-You won't like it. -That's okay.
你聽了一定不高興 沒關係
You got married too fast.
你決定結婚太匆促了
-That's not advice. -I told you.
這算哪們子忠告？ 看吧
I'm going to the bathroom.
我去洗手間
If anyone asked me to give up any of you,I couldn't do it.
要有人叫我別見你們其中一個 我絕對辦不到
Me neither.
我也不行
Maybe I could do it.
或許我可以
嗨 嗨，瑞秋
I know you guys heard about me and Ross.
我知道你們聽說 羅斯跟我的事情了
But I've been obsessing about it and would love not to talk about it.
我已經煩了一整天 請你們別再提起了
I don't know if this falls under that category...
我不知道這算不算提起
...but Ross is right back there.
不過羅斯就在後面
-That's not Ross. -Not that guy.
那才不是羅斯
He does look like him,though.
不是那個，雖然很像
Ross is in the bathroom.
羅斯去洗手間了
Oh,my God! It's happening. It's already started. I'm Kip.
天啊，開始了，現在就這樣， 我就像阿吉
Yeah,you're not Kip.
你才不是阿吉
Do you even know who Kip is?
你知道阿吉是誰嗎？
Who cares? You're Rachel.
誰管他？你是瑞秋
Who's Kip?
阿吉是誰？
My old roommate. We all hung out together.
我以前的室友 以前也跟大家很好
Oh,that poor bastard.
那個可憐人
You told me the story. He and Monica dated.
看吧？你們跟我說過那件事 他以前跟摩妮卡約會
When they broke up,you all promised you'd stay his friend.
分手後卻無法共處一室 你們都答應繼續跟他當朋友
And what happened? He got phased out.
結果呢？他從此遭到排擠
-You won't be phased out. -Of course I am.
我們才不會排擠你 一定會
It won't happen to Ross. He's your brother,your college roommate.
羅斯一定可以留下來 因為他是你哥哥 又是你大學室友
Kip didn't even have to be Kip. We handled that all wrong.
阿吉也不該受到這樣的待遇
我們以前處理得很糟糕
It was a long time ago.
況且那是很久以前的事情
And it was before you and me were around. They didn't know what they were doing.
對啊，瑞秋 當時我跟你還沒出現
他們根本不知道自己在做什麼
Chandler had a mustache, for crying out loud.
錢德還留著小鬍子哩
It was just a matter of time.
遲早有人會離開這個小圈圈
I just assumed Phoebe would be the one to go.
我以前還以為走的是菲比
You live far away, you're not related.
拜託，你住得遠 又不是誰的親戚
You lift right out.
很快就會被淡忘
Hey,Mr. Bing.
賓先生
That hotel you stayed at called.
你住的飯店打電話來
Someone left an eyelash curler in your room.
說在你房間撿到睫毛夾
Yes,that was mine.
是我的
I figured you met a girl and she left it.
我以為你釣上哪個馬子 她忘了帶走
That would have made more sense.
這種說法的確比較合理
I don't even feel like I know you anymore.
我都快要不認識你了
All right,I'm just going to ask you this one time.
我只問你一次就好
Whatever you say, I'll believe you.
無論你怎麼說，我都相信你
Were you or were you not...
你是不是去...
...on a gay cruise?
參加同性戀大會？
菲比
I'm sorry about the whole "lifting out" thing.
我不該說大家會淡忘你
You gotta come with me.
你得跟著我
-Where? -Wherever I go.
去哪裡？ 跟著我就對了
You and me,we'll start a new group. We're the best ones.
我們可以重組一個團體 畢竟我跟你才是精華
Okay,but try to get Joey too.
好吧，不過記得拉喬伊入伙
Phoebe,do you mind if l speak to Rachel alone?
菲比，我可以跟瑞秋 私下談談嗎？
Sure.
當然
Bye,Ross.
再見，羅斯
Forever.
永遠不見了
嗨
Why are you here? Isn't this against the rules?
你來做什麼？這不是違反規定？
I talked to Monica.
我跟摩妮卡談過
Look,I'm the one who made the choice.
是我做這個選擇
I'm the one who's making things change.
我害大家必須要改變
So I should be the one to, you know,step back.
所以離開的應該是我
No,no,it's okay. Really.
羅斯… 真的沒關係
Plenty of people just see their sisters at Thanksgiving...
很多人只有在感恩節見到妹妹
...their college roommates at reunions...
同學會才見到大學室友
...and Joey at Burger King.
在「漢堡王」才見到喬伊
Is that better?
這樣你舒服一點了嗎？
No,it's not better.
一點也沒有
I still don't get to see you.
我還是見不到你
What would you do? If you were me,what would you do?
瑞秋，換做你會怎麼辦？
First,I'd have said the right name at my wedding.
首先，我在婚禮上 就不會說錯名字
I can't believe this.
竟然得走到這一步
I know.
我知道
I am so sorry.
我很抱歉
I know that too.
我也知道
Hey,Rach?
瑞秋
Sorry to interrupt,but Phoebe said you want to talk to me about a trip?
抱歉打擾 菲比說我們要去哪裡
嘿
I just came over to drop off...
嗨 我來拿…
...nothing.
沒事
So that weekend kind of sucked.
上週末過得很糟
Yeah,it did.
沒錯
So I guess this is over?
那大概沒得玩了
You know,you and me. I mean,it had to end sometime.
什麼？
我說你跟我啦 反正遲早得結束
Why exactly?
為什麼？
Because of the weekend. We had a fight.
因為我們上週末吵架啊
Chandler,that's crazy.
錢德，你太扯了
If you always gave up after a fight...
如果你每次吵架就分手
...you'd never be with anyone longer than
交往大概不會超過…
難怪
This isn't over?
所以我們還可以繼續？
You are so cute!
你真可愛
No,no. It was a fight.
當然，我們只是吵架
You deal with it and you move on. It's nothing to freak out about.
吵過之後就算了 根本沒什麼好害怕
Really? Okay,great!
真的？太好了
Welcome to an adult relationship.
歡迎加入成熟戀人行列
We're in a relationship?
我們算是男女朋友？
I'm afraid so.
恐怕是
好吧
嘿
I heard you saw Donald Trump at your convention.
摩妮卡，聽說你上周 看到唐納川普
Saw him waiting for an elevator.
對，我看到他在等電梯
Can I use your eyelash curler? I lost mine.
瑞秋，借我睫毛夾 我的不見了
It's in the bathroom.
好啊，在廁所
Can I talk to you for a second?
喬伊，過來一下
Yes.
沒錯…
You?
你？
And you?
跟你？
But you cannot tell anyone. No one knows.
對，但是你不能告訴別人 還沒人知道
But how? When?
怎麼會？何時？
-lt happened in London. -ln London!
要從倫敦說起 倫敦？
We didn't want to make a big deal out of it.
我們之所以沒告訴大家 是不想你們大驚小怪
But it is a big deal! I have to tell someone!
這的確是大事 我非告訴誰不可
You can't.
不行…你不能說
-Please. Now,I know this is hard. -lt is. It hurts.
我知道這很痛苦 沒錯，痛苦死了
We just don't want to deal with telling everyone.
拜託你，我們就是 不想面對大家質問
Please just promise you won't tell.
求求你保證不說
All right.
好吧
Man,this is unbelievable!
不可思議
I mean,it's great!
這是件好事
But....
可是…
I know. It's great!
我知道，的確很棒
I don't want to see that!
我可不想看到這一幕
We're so stupid.
我們真是太蠢了
Do you know what's going on in there? They're trying to take Joey!
你知道他們在做什麼嗎？他們想搶走喬伊
"The most popular Phoebe in tennis is called the overhand Phoebe.
網球界最有名的菲比 就叫做殺球菲比
If you win,slap your opponent on the Phoebe and say,'Hi,Phoebe!'"
贏了就得跟對方擊掌 說「嗨，菲比」
That's cute. We really all enjoyed it.
真有意思，很好玩
-But it doesn't count. -For what?
但是這不算 不算什麼？
Just count in our heads as good Mad Libs.
這可不算瘋狂字謎
-I gotta go. -Fun's over.
我不想玩了 不好玩了
Wait,if we follow the rules...
等等，要遵守規則
...it's still fun and it means something.
才有意思 也才有意義啊
I'm going to take off.
我要閃人了
Guys,rules are good!
有規則才好
Rules help control the fun.
不守規則怎麼會好玩